# KIM CALDERONE

UX + UI DESIGNER



772.341.0031 kjcalderone@gmail.com www.kimcalderone.com Los Angeles, CA

## SKILLS

#### Research

Heuristic Evaluation User Interviews C&C Analysis Card Sorting

#### Ideation

Persona Development User Flows Information Architecture Wireframing

## Prototyping

Interaction Design App Design Responsive Web Design User Interface Design Usability Testing

# Visual Design

Typography Illustration Sketching

## TOOLS







Invision

Marvel

POPapp







Axure

Sketch

Illustrator





Photoshop Indesign

# ABOUT ME

With a professional background in Graphic Design and User Experience Design, I bring an aesthetically driven and human-centered perspective to every project. I am passionate about creating elegant & thoughtful solutions that users enjoy, no matter the medium.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## UX Design Immersive Studies | General Assembly, 2016

Completed a full-time, 500+ hour study creating user-centered solutions for real world projects using UX methodologies. Projects include:

- Get Stoked! Responsive web design, logo design, & feature integration for the Santa Monica-based swim instruction company.
- Business & Pleasure Mobile app concept for frequent business travelers who have little free time to spend on hotel inconveniences.
- Marbles The Brain Store Responsive web design concept that brings the brick & mortar customer service to the company's online shopping experience.

## Graphic Designer | Fossil Group, 2013-2016

- Designed materials for campaigns, advertisements, and special events across North and South America.
- Developed & tested new processes and best practices guides, which were all eventually adopted by our main corporate office.

## Visual Designer | Freelance, 2012-2016

• Designed digital & print materials for clients from concept to completion, iterating the designs based on feedback every step of the way.

#### Art Coordinator | University Press of Florida, 2011-2013

- Primary director of artwork; editing images, designed book covers, typeset text, and prepared book files for print.
- Streamlined the efficiency of processing images by adopting an assembly line work process and by increasing usability of image schedule chart.

# **EDUCATION**

University of Florida | BFA - Digital Media, 2013